Guide to the Gary Hickling Collection on Lotte Lehmann ARS.0002
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound
- Recordings
  - Works for double bass -- Lieder -- arias., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 26)
    Performers: Hickling, Gary, (?) double bass; Luboshutz, Pierre, 1891-1971, piano. Koussevitzky, Serge, 1874-1951. Selections -- Concerto, double bass, orchestra, op. 3, F# minor, Andante -- Morceaux, double bass, piano, op. 1. Valse miniature --Chanson triste -- Láska, Gustav, 1847-1928. Wiegenlied, double bass, piano, op. 28 -- Eccles, Henry, fl. 1694-1735. Largo -- Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Menuetto in G. Performers: Lehmann, Lotte, soprano; Balogh, Ernö, 1897-, piano. Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Verschweigung; An Chloe -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Im Abendrot -- Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Gesänge, op. 31. Kartenlegerin; Liederkreis, op. 39. Waldesgespräch -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. An die Musik. Performers: Tauber, Richard, 1891-1948, tenor; Branzell, Karin, 1891-1974, alto; Merrem-Nikisch, Grete, 1887-1970, soprano; Staegemann, Max, 1843-1905. Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. Fledermaus -- Side 2: Performers: Gurlitt, Cornelius, 1820-1901, conductor Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Tosca. Selections; Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Turandot. Act 2-3
  - Lotte Lehmann - various songs and Lieder., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 12, Folder 27)
    Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Lieder, op. 49. Wiegenlied -- Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Kinderscenen. Träumerei -- Berlin, Irving, 1888- God bless America -- Days of the Carry Dancing -- unidentified -- Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Lieder und Gesänge, op. 51. Ich wand're nicht -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Selections -- Schwanengesang (Song cycle). Ständchen -- An den Mond, op. 57, no. 3 -- Jüngling an der Quelle -- An die Nachtigall, D. 497 -- Refrainlieder. Männer sind méchant.
  - Lotte Lehmann Farewell Recital, New Yok City 1951., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 12, Folder 28)
    Introductory speech by Lotte Lehmann. Performers: Lotte Lehmann, soprano; Paul Ulanowsky, piano. Franz, Robert, 1815-1892. Selections -- Gesänge, op. 10. Für Musik -- Gesänge, op. 17. Ständchen -- Gesänge, op. 5. Gute Nacht -- Weisst du noch? -- Volkstümliche Lieder -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Schöne Müllerin. Selections -- Wohin? -- Danksagung an den Bach -- Neugierige -- Tränenregen -- Die liebe Farbe.
  - Music Academy of the West. Fifth Festival Concert, Aug. 7, 1951., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 12, Folder 29)
    Performers: Lehmann, Lotte, soprano; Koldofsky, Gwendolyn, piano. Lobero Theatre, Santa Barbara Calif. Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Selections -- An die Musik -- An mein Clavier -- Schöne Müllerin. Neugierige -- Im Abendrot -- Seligkeit -- Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Gesänge, op. 86. Mond; Lieder, op. 57. Venetianisches Gondellied -- Cornelius, Peter, 1824-1874. Trauer und Trost. Ton; Lieder, op. 1. Wiegenlied -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Wesendonck-Lieder. Träume -- Hahn, Reynaldo, 1875-1947. Selections -- A nos morts ignores -- Pholoe -- Phillis -- Offrande -- Le rosignol des Lilas -- Si mes veis -- Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Selections -- Gesänge, op. 43. Mainacht -- Gesänge, op. 70. Lerchengesang -- Lieder und Gesänge, op. 57. Es träumte mir, ich sei dir teuer -- Lieder, op. 47. Botschaft -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 27. Morgen.
  - Lotte Lehmann, various selctions., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 12, Folder 30)
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Ich ruf' zu dir, Herr Jesu Christ (Cantata) (?) -- Rössel, ?. Wo du hingehst -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Wesendonck-Lieder. Im Treibhaus -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. An die Musik; Sei mir gegrüsst! -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 27. Cäcilie -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tannhäuser. Dich, teure Halle -- Lehár, Franz, 1870-1948. Eva. Wär' es auch nichts als ein Augenblick (Melodram und Lied: So war meine Mutter recit.; Wär es auch nichts als ein Augenblick, Waltz aria) --
  - Lotte Lehmann on Richard Strauss., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 12, Folder 31)
    WBAI. Radio Program. Exceprt of a Lotte Lehman Masterclass in England. Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 27. Heimliche Aufforderung -- BBC Conversation with Lotte Lehmann and John Amos (sp?) on her work with Richard Strauss. Vienna State Opera, 1933 recording. Performers: Heger, Robert, conductor Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier (Opera). Da geht er hin; Hab' mir's gelobt, ihn lieb zu haben.
  - Various opera excerpts., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 12, Folder 32)
    Lehár, Franz, 1870-1948. Zigeunerliebe (?) -- Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Tosca -- etc.
  - Lotte Lehmann's 85th birthday celebration., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, half-track, mono.; 5 in. (Box 12, Folder 33)
    Conversation on Lotte Lehmann's career. Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Werther.
  - Lotte Lehmann's New York City farewell, Feb. 16, 1951. (final portion), 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, half-track, mono.; 5 in. (Box 12, Folder 34)
    Town Hall. Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Schöne Müllerin. Des Baches Wiegenlied; An die Musik.
  - Lotte Lehmann sings popular songs., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, half-track, mono.; 5 in. (Box 12, Folder 35)
    Side 1: Eine kleine Liebelei -- Frühling ist es wieder -- Es gibt eine Frau die ich niemals vergib -- Ich hol dir von Himmel das Blau -- Der Duft der eine schöne Frau -- Wenn du einmal dein Herz verschenkst -- Varlamov, Aleksandr Egorovich, 1801-1848. Rote Sarafan (?) -- Es waren zwei Königskinder. Side 2: 's Zuschaun -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 27. Morgen -- Gruber, Franz Xaver, 1787-1863. Stille Nacht, heilige Nacht -- Ratzinger, Georg. O du fröhliche.
  - Lotte Lehmann masterclass Widmore Hall, London Mar.3-15, 1964., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Lotte Lehmann various interviews., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Lotte Lehmann teaching art song and discussion on Richard Strauss., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Lotte Lehmann: Interveiw with Haussmann., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Lotte Lehmann 85th birthday tribute. Part I of IV, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Lotte Lehmann 85th birthday tribute. Part II of IV, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Lotte Lehmann 85th birthday tribute. Part IV of IV, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Lotte Lehmann New York City farewell, 1951., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier, Act I., 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Bodanzky, Artur, 1877-1939, conductor. Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier.
    Edward J. Smith Records. The Golden Age of Opera
  - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier, Act III, 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier. Bodanzky, Artur, 1877-1939, conductor.
  - Beethoven. Fidelio, Act I, 1935., 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Fidelio (1805). Toscanini, Arturo, 1867-1957, conductor
    Edward J. Smith Records. Unique Opera Records.
  - Mercadante. Elisa e Claudio. Part 3 and 4, 1935., 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Rapalo, Ugo, conductor. Mercadante, Saverio, 1795-1870. Elisa e Claudio.
  - Strauss. Rosenkavalier. Act I, 1939., 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    Bodanzky, Artur, 1877-1939, conductor Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier.
    T (Private Record)
  - Strauss. Rosenkavalier. Act II, 1939., 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Strauss. Rosenkavalier. Act III, 1939., 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Lotte Lehmann. Town Hall Farewell Recital, Feb. 16, 1951., 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    Performer: Ulanowsky, Paul, 1908-1968, piano. Side 1: Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Selections -- Myrthen. Widmung -- O, Ihr Herren -- Gedichte, op. 36. Ständchen -- Gedichte, op. 35. Wer machte dich so krank? -- Gedichte, op. 35. Alte Laute -- Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Gesänge, op. 86. Mond; Lieder, op. 57. Venetianisches Gondellied -- Cornelius, Peter, 1824-1874. Trauer und Trost. Ton; Lieder, op. 1. Wiegenlied -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Wesendonck-Lieder. Träume -- Lehmann's Farewell speech. Side 2: Franz, Robert, 1815-1892. Selections -- Gesänge, op. 10. Für Musik -- Gesänge, op. 17. Ständchen -- Gesänge, op. 5. Gute Nacht -- Weisst Du Noch -- Dies und Das --Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Selections -- Schöne Müllerin. Wohin? -- Danksagung an den Bach -- Neugierige --Tränenregen -- Liebe Farbe -- Des Baches Wiegenlied -- An die Musik.
  - Lotte Lehmann sings Lieder I., 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    Test Pressing of Radio Program. Lotte Lehmann introduces and sings various Lieder. Performer: Ulanowsky, Paul, 1908-1968, piano. Side 1: Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Selections -- Andenken -- Gesänge, op. 83. Wonne der Wehmut -- Egmont. Trommel gerühret -- Kuss -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Selections -- An die Musik. -- Schwanengesang (Song cycle). Ständchen -- Erlkönig -- Side 2: Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Selections -- Gesänge, op. 34. Auf Flügeln des Gesanges -- Gesänge, op. 19a. Neue Liebe -- Lieder, op. 57. Venetianisches Gondellied -- Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Selections -- Abendempfindung -- Veilchen -- Männer suchen stets zu naschen
    Allied Record Company
  - Lotte Lehmann sings Lieder II., 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    Test Pressing of Radio Program. Lotte Lehmann introduces and sings various Lieder. Performer: Ulanowsky, Paul, 1908-1968, piano. Side 1: Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Winterreise. Selections -- Gute Nacht -- Frühlingstraum -- Leiermann -- Liederkreis, op. 39. In der Fremde (No. 1) --Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Dichterliebe. Ich grolle nicht -- Myrthen. Nussbaum --Lieder und Gesänge, op. 77. Aufträge -- Side 1: Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Selections -- Gesänge, op. 43. Mainacht -- Lieder, op. 106. Ständchen -- Lieder, op. 49. Wiegenlied -- Lieder, op. 47. O liebliche Wangen -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Selections -- Wesendonck-Lieder. Schmerzen -- Im Treibhaus -- Träume.
  - Lotte Lehmann sings Lieder III., 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    Test Pressing of Radio Program. Lotte Lehmann introduces and sings various Lieder. Performer: Ulanowsky, Paul, 1908-1968, piano. Side 1: Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903. Selections -- Mörike-Lieder. Gesang Weylas -- Verborgenheit -- Spanisches Liederbuch. Wer tat deinem Füsslein weh? -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Selections -- Lieder, op. 10. Allerseelen -- Lieder, op. 10. Zueignung -- Lieder, op. 17. Ständchen -- Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Selections -- Sehnsucht nach dem Frühlinge -- An die Einsamkeit -- Dans un bois solitaire -- Side 2: Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Schwanengesang (Song cycle). Doppelgänger -- Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Myrthen. Lotosblume -- Flies, Bernhard. Wiegenlied -- Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Romanzen und Lieder, op. 84. Vergebliches Ständchen -- Distler, Hugo, 1908-1942. Weihnachtsgeschichte. Es ist ein Ros entsprungen -- Ratzinger, Georg. O du fröhliche -- Gruber, Franz Xaver, 1787-1863. Stille Nacht, heilige Nacht.
  - Music Academy of the West. Fifth Festival Concert. Mme. Lotte Lehmann, Aug. 7, 1951., 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    Private Pressing. Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Selections -- An mein Klavier --Schöne Müllerin. Neugierige -- Fischerweise -- Im Abendrot -- Seligkeit --Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Gesänge, op. 86. Mond; Lieder, op. 57. Venetianisches Gondellied -- Cornelius, Peter, 1824-1874. Trauer und Trost. Ton; Lieder, op. 1. Wiegenlied -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Wesendonck-Lieder. Träume -- Hahn, Reynaldo, 1875-1947. Selections -- A Nos Morts Ignores -- Pholoe -- Phillis -- Offrande -- Le Rosignol des Lilas -- Si mes vers -- Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Selections -- Gesänge, op. 43. Mainacht -- Gesänge, op. 70. Lerchengesang -- Lieder und Gesänge, op. 57. Es träumte mir, ich sei dir teuer -- Lieder, op. 47. Botschaft -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 27. Morgen.
  - Bruno Walter accompanies Lotte Lehmann and Kathleen Ferrier., 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    Private Pressing. Side 1: Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Selections -- Junge Nonne -- Du liebst mich nicht -- Tod und das Mädchen (Song) -- Rosamunde. Romanze --Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Lieder, op. 105. Immer leiser wird mein Schlummer; Lieder, op. 96. Tod, das ist die kühle Nacht -- Side 2: Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Selections -- Lieder, op. 106. Ständchen -- Gesänge, op. 34. Auf Flügeln des Gesanges -- Lieder, op. 49. Wiegenlied -- Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Lieder und Gesänge, op. 77. Aufträge.
    Bruno Walter Society Records
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Nozze di Figaro. Crudel! perchè finora., 1 sound disc: 78 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Nozze di Figaro. Crudel! perchè finora. Sung in German.
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Nozze di Figaro. Crudel! perchè finora., 1 sound disc: 78 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 14, Folder 16)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Nozze di Figaro. Crudel! perchè finora. Sung in German. (duplicate)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Don Giovanni. Là ci darem la mano., 1 sound disc: 78 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 14, Folder 17)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Don Giovanni. Là ci darem la mano (sung in German)
    .
  - Lotte Lehmann - Lieder., 1 sound disc: 33 and 78 rpm, acetate; 12 in. (Box 14, Folder 18)
    Transcription disc. Side three (sic): Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Selections -- Andenken -- In questa tomba oscura -- Kuss -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Schöne Müllerin. Neugierige -- Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903. Mörike-Lieder. Verborgenheit -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 10. Allerseelen; Lieder, op. 10. Zueignung. Unmarked side: Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Gesänge, op. 34. Auf Flügeln des Gesanges; Gesänge, op. 19a. Neue Liebe -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Wesendonck-Lieder. Engel -- Im Treibhaus (fragment) Original disc dustcover annotated: Job no 77586. Lotte Lehmann. Reel III. For Paul Myers
  - Lotte Lehmann - God Bless America., 1 sound disc: 33 and 78 rpm, acetate; 12 in. (Box 14, Folder 19)
    Transcription disc. No.3965 Transcription disc. Berlin, Irving, 1888- God bless America
    Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer
  - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier, Act II, 1 sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Carton 14, Folder 20)